Guide to the Rice University Scientia Organizational Papers, 1980-2016, UA 206 UA 206
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Scientia Organizational Papers
1980-2016
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Pomerantz, Jim
UA 206
3 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
This collection is composed of organizational papers relating to the Scientia Institute at Rice University. It includes copies of the organization's charter, by-laws, membership lists, speakers, correspondence, meeting minutes, audio/visual materials, and general information.
Historical Note
Scientia: An Institute for the History of Science and Culture was conceived by Salomon Bochner and Albert van Helden in 1980. Its purpose is to promote scholarship and research in the general area of history of science and culture for the benefit of the university and Houston community. Its activities include sponsoring the Bochner Lectures on an annual or biannual basis; sponsoring Scientia Colloquia lectures on a regular basis throughout the year; and formal and informal meetings between the organizational members for discussion and formation of policy.
Excerpted from the Scientia Charter. For more information, see http://scientia.rice.edu.
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed of 3 boxes of documents and electronic media that document the internal business of Scientia and activities undertaken by the organization to fulfill its mission of promoting scholarship and research in the area of history of science and culture to benefit the Houston community. Documents and materials are in good condition and include charters, by-laws, memberships lists, other business papers, correspondence, lecture programs, and audio, video and electronic media.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transfered to the Woodson Research Center by Scientia members Franz R. Brotzen, Ronnie O. Wells, Albert Van Helden, Susan K. McIntosh, and Jim Pomerantz.
Related Materials
There is some administrative overlap with the DeLange Conference Collection (UA 263).
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
minutes (administrative records)
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Business Papers and Membership, 213623
  - Charter and Tasks, 1983-2000; 95340 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - By-Laws and Membership Revision - 1994, 95341 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership Lists, 1984-2008; 95342 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C.P. Snow Student Fellows, 2006-2009; 95343 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - C.P. Snow Faculty Fellows, 2006-2009; 95344 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Members' Curriculum Vitae: A - M, n.d.; 95345 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Members' Curriculum Vitae: N - Z, n.d.; 95346 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1982-1984; 95347 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1985-1989; 95351 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1990-1993; 95352 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1994-1999; 95353 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 2000-2004; 95354 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 2005-2008; 95355 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Grant Proposal, 1992; 95356 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2005-2008 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series III: Programs
  - Programs and publicity, 1982-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs and publicity, 1996-2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Programs and publicity, 2005-2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bochner Lectures, 1983-2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Colloquium, 1994-04-09 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Addendum: Minutes, Correspondence, Programs
  - Minutes, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Programs and publicity, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series V: Audio, Video, and Electronic Media
  - Scientia minutes, programs, 1994-1999 (Box 3, Disc 1)
  - Bochner Lecture, Alastair Norcross, 2005 (Box 3, Disc 2)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 1/3, 1994-04-09 (Box 3, Tape 3)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 1/3, 1994-04-09 (Box 3, Tape 4)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 2 (Box 3, Tape 5)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 3 (Box 3, Tape 6)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 3 (Box 3, Tape 7)
  - David Schneider - Psychology of Violence, 2005-03-15 (Box 3, Tape 8)
  - Rick Wilson: "In Others We Trust", 2005-02-15 (Box 3, Tape 9)
  - Kirsten Ostherr: "Violence in the Mass Media", 2005-01-18 (Box 3, Tape 10)
  - Richard J. Stoll - Do "Nice States" Finish Last?, 2004-12-07 (Box 3, Tape 11)
  - David Cook: "Does Jihad Mean Violence?", 2004-11-16 (Box 3, Tape 12)
  - Dr. Lee Silver, Bochner Lecture, Duncan Hall, 2004-03-15 (Box 3, Tape 13)
  - Scientia Colloquium, "The Viral University" - Frank Huband, Executive Director Am Society for Engineering Edu, 2000-01-18 (Box 3, Tape 14)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 2 of 3, 1994-08-09 (Box 3, Tape 15)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 3 of 3, 1994-04-09 (Box 3, Tape 16)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 1 of 3, 1994-04-09 (Box 3, Tape 17)
  - The Teaching of Science in a University Curriculum, Tape 2 of 3, 1994-04-09 (Box 3, Tape 18)
  - George Rupp - "Local Conflicts/Global Challenge, 2005-04-19 (Box 3, Tape 19)
  - C.J. Peters, M.D., 2006-01-17 (Box 3, Tape 20)
  - Alastair Norcross - Puppies, Pigs, and People, 2005-09-13 (Box 3, Tape 21)
  - Alastair Norcross - Puppies, Pigs, and People, 2005-09-13 (Box 3, Tape 22)